CONTACT

SHAIAH EMIGH-DOYLE

sde2111@columbia.edu

(207) 479-7090

Full-Stack Software Developer

NYC or Remote

m shaiahwren.com

github.com/ShaiahWren

linkedin.com/in/shaiah-emigh-doyle

EDUCATION

DIGITALCRAFTS

July 2020 - Nov 2020

Full-stack software development course for creating web applications with a JavaScript full-stack including Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, React, Redux, Python, HTML and CSS.

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY

New York, NY 2018 - 2020

Master of Arts in Anthropology GPA: 3.90

SMITH COLLEGE

Northampton, MA 2012 - 2016

Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology & Arabic GPA: 3.92

SKILLS

Tools, Technologies, & Expertise

- Python
- JavaScript
- CSS/HTML
- Node.js
- Express
- PostgreSQL
- React/Redux
- Git/Github
- Responsive Design
- RESTful API
- Responsive Design

Foreign Languages

- Hebrew
- Arabic
- Swahili
- Spanish
- English

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack developer dedicated to producing software and excellent user experience. A critical thinker with a passion for learning, an Anthropologist and linguist with international experience, I bring a diverse and unique set of skills to any project or team environment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DIGITAL CRAFTS

Full-stack Software Developer | July 2020 - Nov 2020

VivaLingua

vivalingua.dev | github.com/ShaiahWren/Viva Lingua | September 2020

- Built a full-stack application for crowdsourcing information about four endangered languages.
- Primary team roles included PostgreSQL, Back-end & Front-end development, and Lead styling/design.

Quiz Yo'self

<u>quiz-yoself.com</u> | <u>github.com/ShaiahWren/Quiz-Yoself</u> | August 2020

- Collaborated with three other developers to build a trivia website
- The application was built from scratch using vanilla JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, and an API. Implemented all the design and styling elements and produced a fully responsive web application.

Fun Fair Danger

github.com/ShaiahWren/fun fair danger | August 2020

- Worked on a team of four to build a terminal-based Python game.
- Took full responsibility for creating the 'wizard room,' in which I led the user through a series of riddles, interrogations, and cyphers.

More projects at: My Portfolio | My Github

LENFEST CENTER FOR THE ARTS, COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY

Wardrobe Technician | Sept 2019 - Nov 2020

Collaborated with costume designers, wardrobe supervisor, and student staff to create professional costumes for director thesis productions. Utilized hand stitching and machine sewing skills.

JACOBSON CENTER, SMITH COLLEGE

Arabic Teaching Assistant | 2013 - Nov 2016

Tutored first-third year Smith students individually in Arabic speaking, reading, and writing skills. Achieved high performance improvements among tutees Established effective, individualized language-learning support.